

Hermino Barbosa de Freitas Júnior

City: Manaus - AM

Email: herminojunior@gmail.com **Telephone:** +5595991741019

PROFILE

Full Stack Developer with over 5+ years of experience across a wide range of technologies. Currently developing in React.js and Node.js for the frontend, and Python with Flask, FastAP and Django for the backend. Experienced in using PostgreSQL as a database as well as project infrastructure, including deployment on production servers with Linux systems. Previous experience with Angular, Spring Boot, ASP.NET and databases such as PostgreSQL and SQL Server. Committed to continuous skill improvement and professional growth. A dedicated employee with team spirit, open to continuous learning and eager to contribute positively and effectively to the team and the company.

EDUCATION

Computer Science,

Federal University of Roraima - UFRR - (04/2022)

IT Technician,

Federal Institute of Education, Science and Technology of Roraima – IFRR - (12/2016)

EXPERIENCE

Developer II,

INDT - Institute for Technological Development - (02/2022 - today)

"I joined the company as a junior and spent 5 months helping team members with their tasks, the project's API and evaluating the interns' deliveries. After this period, there was a demand for the development of a web platform. As most of the team was focused on AI and testing, I quickly stood out and took over the end-to-end development of this tool. After 9 months at home, I received a promotion to full level, achieved due to the high volume of deliveries and extra activities carried out."

- Participation in a collaborative project with Motorola working in multi-functions.
- Active performance in several key areas.
- Development of a web tool for natural language processing.
- Experience in Frontend, Backend, Database and Infrastructure Management.
- Use of technologies such as Python, Typescript, Javascript, SQL, Flask, FastAPI, React, Node.js, SQLite database, PostgreSQL.

Junior Systems Development Analyst, Northern Institute of Technology and Business - ITN -(08/2020 - 02/2022)

"I worked on 6 projects, all with Angular 8+ on the frontend, 3 with Spring Boot and 3 with ASP.NET on the backend. The projects with ASP.NET were R&D projects, legacy and prior to my Entering the company, with little material about the scope and limited knowledge about the technology used, I faced this challenge alone. Furthermore, to meet customer demands, there were daily interactions. Barriers were overcome and projects were delivered. The other 3 projects were well-established products with small daily deliveries."

- Creation of web systems with an emphasis on computer vision services.
- Involvement in 6 projects with Frontend, Backend, Database and Infrastructure.
- Use of tools and technologies:

Programming languages: Java, C#, Typescript, Javascript, SQL. Frameworks e libraries: Spring Boot, ASP.NET, Angular, Node.js. Containerization: Docker.

Databases: PostgreSQL, SQL Server.

Student Researcher,

Federal University of Roraima - UFRR - (08/2017 - 04/2022)

"After the end of the second semester, I received an invitation to participate in a research project. The first research involved recognizing emotions in still images using OpenCV and scikit-learn. Later, the focus shifted to developing recommendation systems for online judges to assist students using these platforms. Over these more than 4 years of research, I received the award for best article and best conclusion work."

- Development of research in data mining, machine learning and education.
- I use Python and SQL languages, along with libraries such as pandas, matplotlib and scikit-learn, in an Anaconda environment.
- Working on the development of recommendation systems and also with natural language processing.
- I generated 6 articles from these studies.
- Best article of 2019 at SBIE and best conclusion work at CTD-IE.

INFORMATION

English: Intermediary

GitHub: https://github.com/hermino

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/hermino/

SKILLS

Soft skills:

- Collaboration and teamwork;
- Research and analysis;

Hard skills:

- End-to-End web developer;
- Liguagens: Python, Typescript, C#, Java, Javascript, SQL;
- Frameworks/Bibliotecas: Flask, FastAPI, React, Angular,
 .NET, Spring Boot;
- Database: SQLite, PostgreSQL, MySQL.